A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal, Series Z FA335
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Scrapbooks, 1895-1960; 9; 22 Bound Volumes
  - Volume 11, June 1926-January 1929 (Reel M 26, Frame M 11)
    Rockefeller Children (Includes statements by Jr. on bringing up children), 2-4, 6-7, 10-11, 20-23, 24-25, 28-29, 31, 53-56, 62, 88, 127, 175, 194
    Rockefeller Foundation, 166
    Rockefeller, J. D., Sr., 20-25, 38, 58, 63, 174
    St. Joseph's Normal College, 170A
    Seal Harbor, 174
    Senate Coal Investigation, 90-94
    Shakespeare Memorial Theatre, 47-48, 156
    Spelman Chapel, 29, 32-37, 43-44
    Steward Case, 65-88, 94-95, 98, 100-124, 132, 135-137, 151, 154-166, 170B, 173
    Tarrytown (See also "Pocantico" and "Apartment Project in North Tarrytown"), 54, 57-58, 64-65, 85, 115-116, 118, 119, 173, 189
    Trip to California and Oregon in 1926, 1-8
    Trip to Duluth and Iron Range, 170B
    Trip to Europe in 1927, 42, 53-56
    University of Chicago Address at Dedication of Chapel, 178, 180-186
    Versailles (See also "Rheims"), 172, 189
    Westchester County Park Commission Gift, 85, 88
    Western Maryland Railroad, 19, 21, 23
    Williamsburg, 56-60, 63, 65, 121, 127, 129-130, 136, 167-170A, 174-179, 187-188, 191-192
    YMCA, 57-58
  - Volume 12, January 1929-December 1930 (Reel M 26, Frame M 12)
    Acadia National Park, 157
    Architects, American Institute of - JDR, Jr. honorary member, 135-136
    Broadway Temple, 2-3
    Brown University, 143, 149
    Byrd Polar Expeditions, 60, 98-101
    Catholic Charities, 104, 108-109, 113-114, 137
    Chamber of Commerce Citation, 117-119
    Cloisters, The, 173 (George Gray Barnard)
    Emergency Employment Comm., 162-163, 172
    Fort Tryon Park, 138-143, 150
    Gates, F. T., 43-44, 48, 52
    George Washington Birthplace - See "Wakefield Estate"
    Jackson Hole, 131B
    Jerusalem Museum, 68, 71
    Laymen's Foreign Mission Inquiry, 158
    Lying-In Hospital, 65
    Macy, V. Everit, Memorial, 131B
    Mayor - Suggestion of JDR, Jr., 111
    Metropolitan Opera House - See "Rockefeller Center"
    Mother Jones, 132-133, 152-153
    Mount Desert, 101, 108
    Park Avenue Baptist Church, 110
    Pocantico - See "Tarrytown"
    Princeton University, 131-133
    Real Estate Projects, 52, 93, 96, 129-130, 158-159, 164, 171
    Redwoods, 46, 59
    Rockefeller Center, 2, 19, 25-26, 29-38, 42, 54, 142, 144-149, 151, 160, 163, 170
    Rockefeller Children, 104, 108, 119-126, 136-137, 183
    Riverside Church, 96, 111, 119-120, 131, 134, 154, 156, 158, 165-170, 173, 175-181
    Rockefeller Foundation, 2-5, 27, 108
    Rockefeller, J. D., Sr., 11, 116, 127, 146
    Seal Harbor (See also "Mount Desert" and "Acadia National Park"), 106, 107
    Spelman Memorial, 2-5, 27
    Stewart Case, 3-9, 12-24, 37-57, 60-98, 102-105
    Stock, buying of in 1929, 114-115
    Tarrytown, 11, 101, 102, 109-110, 112, 116, 125, 126, 128, 131A, 132-135, 137, 155-157, 165, 170-171
    Trip to Egypt, 1929, 1, 3, 5, 25-30, 41, 68, 81, 93
    Trip to Europe, 1930, 160-162
    Trip to Palestine, 1929, 68, 71, 90
    University of Tokyo, 105, 109
    Versailles, 1, 113B, 160-161, 170, 172
    Wakefield Estate, 49-50, 53, 56-60, 90
    Williamsburg, 102-103, 113, 126-127
  - Volume 13, January 1931-November 1933 (Reel M 27, Frame M 13)
    Acadia National Park, 1, 3, 6-7, 21
    Arizona Trip - 1931, 7, 8, 15, 18, 20-21
    Belgium - Plaque to JDR, Jr., 1
    Brown University, 1, 22-23, 25
    Cairo Museum, 122
    Chase National Bank, 130
    Claremont Park, 47
    Colorado Fuel and Iron, 193, 196
    Colorado Strike, 39
    Dunbar Apartments, 30
    Emergency Unemployment Relief, 128-129
    Fontainebleau, 27
    Fort Tryon, 10, 142-143, 159
    "Greatest Need of Business Today," 48
    Industrial Relations, 193, 196
    International House - Chicago, 115
    Jackson Hole, 29, 35, 151, 167-168, 170-171, 177, 189
    Jury Duty, 43
    Laboratory of Anthropology at Santa Fe, 19, 31
    Laymen's Foreign Mission Inquiry, 32, 34, 118, 121
    Macy, V. Everit, Park, 50
    McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 102, 106-114
    Metropolitan Museum, 135, 138, 140-141
    Mt. Desert - See "Acadia National Park"
    New York Historical Society, 24
    NRA Broadcast, 172, 174-179, 187
    Oriental Institute, 42
    Palisades, 152, 154, 158-166, 169-171, 173
    Pocantico, 20, 43
    Prohibition, 51, 55-105, 139, 153, 155-157, 175-177, 180-181, 183-191, 196, 201
    Redwoods, 23-24, 51
    Rheims, 150
    Riverside Church, 4, 22, 47, 48, 50, 107, 119-120
    Rockefeller, Abby A., 40-41
    Rockefeller Center, 190
    Rockefeller Children (Includes statements by Jr. on bringing up children), 43, 122, 127
    Rockefeller, J. D., Sr., 31, 52-54, 144
    Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 8
    Rosenberger Medal, 22, 25
    Siam, King of, 24-25
    Sports, 5-6, 33
    Tarrytown (See also "Pocantico"), 1, 8, 10, 34, 36, 38, 40, 109, 118, 147
    Unemployment Relief Committee Gift, 36-38
    University of Chicago, 123
    Versailles, 27, 186, 191, 194-196, 198-200
    Welch, William H., 2
    Westchester County, Gift to, 36
    Williamsburg, 12-14, 22, 37, 46, 47, 114-117, 136, 182-183, 193
    Yellowstone, 141
    Yosemite, 23
  - Volume 14, November 1933-July 1936 (Reel M 27, Frame M 14)
    Acadia National Park, 25
    Berkman, Alexander, 173-175
    Breasted, Dr. J. H., 141-142
    Cite Universitaire, 152-158, 167
    Claremont Park, 28
    Cloisters, The, 80-88, 114, 117, 124-126
    Council for Moderation, 109, 111, 119, 142, 143, 144
    Dancing (JDR, Jr.), 139
    Ethiopian Oil Concessions Cancellation, 105-109
    Fingerprinting, 71-73
    Fontainebleau, 5
    Fort Tryon Park, 17, 31, 79, 110, 118, 120-122, 139, 163
    Fortune, July, 1936 Article on JDR, Jr., 189-202
    Four West 54th Street, 134-136, 141
    Gasser, Dr. H. S., 111, 115
    Gifts of over $25,000,000 in stock in 1935, 102-109
    Great Smokies, 51
    Gridiron Club, 90-91
    Industrial Relations, 78
    International House, Paris, 77
    Jackson Hole, 26, 29, 39
    Jerusalem Museum, 88
    Jewels, 9, 53
    Lee, Ivy, 56
    McCormick, Edith Rockefeller, 9, 10, 101 (her children)
    Memorial Hospital, 159-163, 165
    Metropolitan Museum Concerts, 136, 146
    Northern Baptist Convention, 117-118, 122-123, 126-131, 133, 136-138, 143, 144
    Oriental Institute, 141-142
    Palisades, The, 89-93, 95, 182
    Presidential Nomination, Suggestion, 109
    Prohibition, 1-4, 184-187
    Real Estate Projects, 127, 132, 159, 167, 202
    Rheims, 5, 146, 151
    Rockefeller Center, 1, 6-7, 10, 23, 27, 28, 31, 33, 39, 71, 74, 179-181
    Rockefeller Children, 32, 44, 52, 71, 73, 74-76, 96-99, 121, 142, 149
    Rockefeller, J. D., Jr., General Articles, 145-148, 189-202
    Rockefeller, J. D., Sr., 6, 30, 32, 39, 44-45, 117, 146, 150, 172-173, 175-176
    Rockefeller, Percy, 51-55
    Stock - JDR, Jr.'s holdings, 69-70, 79
    Tarrytown, 6, 14, 30, 45, 47, 56, 59
    Trip to Europe 1936, 183-186, 202-203
    Trip to Italy 1935, 83
    Trip to Sicily 1934, 17, 29, 59
    Union Theological Seminary, 140
    Versailles, 5, 40-43, 115, 168-174, 176-178, 183, 187, 194
    Williamsburg, 4, 11-27, 30, 34-37, 46-51, 56-58, 60-69, 73, 75, 94-95, 112-114, 117, 133, 150-151, 161, 164, 166-167
  - Volume 15, August 1936-May 1939 (Reel M 27, Frame M 15)
    Agora, 28, 34, 116-117
    Archaeological Gifts, 34
    Art, 139
    Bible Class, 60
    Birthday - 63rd, 48-53
    Brown University, 73-74, 85-87, 89
    Chamber of Commerce Dinner and Award, 182-183
    Cleveland Museum of Art, 127, 131, 137-138
    Cloisters, The, 125, 135, 164, 168
    Colorado Trip, 62
    Distinguished Service for Conservation Award, 174
    Dunbar Apartments, 14-15, 17, 19, 21, 26-28, 48, 71, 107
    Euclid Avenue Baptist Church, 12, 13-14, 16
    Euclid Avenue Home (Barn), 146
    Forest Hill Park, 86, 134, 141, 169-170
    Fort Tryon Park, 175
    Four West 54th Street - Tearing Down, 127, 129, 139
    General Education Board, 145
    George VI and Queen Elizabeth Visit, 175, 194-196
    Great Smokies, 146, 150-151, 153, 190-191
    Greater New York Fund, 189
    Gridiron Dinner, Washington, 29-32
    Industrial Relations, 61
    Interdenominationalism, 53, 55-58, 63-68, 73-76, 92-93, 121
    International House - New York, 105-110, 114-116
    International House - Paris, 21, 26
    Legion of Honor Award, 14
    Lenten Vesper Service Speech, 60, 62-68, 73
    Memorial Hospital, 70, 126, 185
    Metropolitan Museum, 180
    Oriental Institute, 34, 154
    Peking Union Medical College, 118-119
    Philipse Manor, 197
    Presidential Nomination, Speculation regarding, 145-147, 177, 180, 182
    Prohibition, 2, 22
    Real Estate Projects, 14-15, 17, 19, 21, 26-28, 48, 71, 101
    Republican Party - Contribution to, 1, 4-8, 10-12, 20, 23-26, 35
    Rheims, 82-83, 104-105, 129-130, 136, 148-149
    Riverside Church, 189-191
    Rockefeller Brothers, 59, 100-101, 103, 132, 141-145, 149, 186-188
    Rockefeller Center, 36-47, 54, 91, 107, 117, 120-121, 124-125, 128, 157-160, 162, 164, 166, 172-173, 176, 179
    Rockefeller Foundation, 128
    Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Series of general articles about, 88, 94-101
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 76-81, 83-84, 161-168
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr. - Memorial at Tarrytown, 190, 193
    Rockefeller Rooms (from 4 West 54th Street given to City Museum), 193
    "Rockefeller Wives," 101-102
    Seal Harbor, 91, 152
    740 Park Avenue - Move to, 16-19, 122-123, 139, 147
    Tarrytown (See also "Lenten Vesper Service Speech" and "JDR, Sr. Memorial), 53, 69-71, 111-113, 115, 119, 125, 170, 178-179, 181-182, 189
    Ten West 54th Street - Move from, 16-19, 122-123, 139, 147
    Unemployment Census, 105, 109
    University of Chicago, 47
    Versailles, 3, 13-15, 28, 155-157
    Williamsburg, 10, 27, 33, 61, 72, 107-108, 124, 140, 175
    World's Fair Bonds, 47
    World's Fair Temple of Religion, 159-161, 171-174, 178, 184
    YMCA, 164
  - Volume 16, January 1940-October 1941 (Reel M 27, Frame M 16)
    Alcoholics Anonymous, 104
    Barnard, George Gray, 35
    Boy Scouts, 117-118
    Browning School, 6
    Byrd Polar Expeditions, 125
    Casements, The - See "Ormond Beach"
    Chamber of Commerce Award (Tarrytown), 11-12, 26, 30-33, 39, 43-44
    Cloisters, The, 35, 37, 45-55, 122-124, 164, 168
    Dashiell, Lefferts, 8-9
    Dunbar Apartments, 29, 35, 38
    Euclid Avenue Home, 6-8, 20, 23, 26
    Finnish Relief, 106-107
    Forest Hill Park, 17, 20, 36, 187
    Forgery of JDR, Jr.'s Name, 148-149, 163, 166, 169
    General Education Board, 16-17
    Great Smokies, 70, 122, 128
    Greater New York Fund, 7-8, 10-12, 48, 121
    Industrial Relations, 7, 12, 14-17
    International House, 75
    King, W. L. Mackenzie, 170
    Lakewood Estate - Gift to Ocean County, 126
    Ocean County - Gift of Lakewood Estate, 126
    Orange Trees - Gift to Park in Boston, 76-77
    Ormond Beach Home, 142-143
    Palestine Museum, 3, 6-8
    Palisades, 117-118, 144
    Philipse Castle, 103-106, 108-113, 120-121, 126, 155, 166, 171
    Presidential Nomination, Speculation Regarding, 1, 2, 17, 57, 87
    Riverside Church, 144, 150
    Rockefeller, Abby, 30
    Rockefeller Brothers, 11, 13, 14, 118, 125, 131-137, 140, 142, 145-148, 151, 160, 193
    Rockefeller Center, 3-5, 40-42, 70, 72, 77-101, 107, 153
    Rockefeller Foundation, 16-17, 32, 54, 107, 113-118, 128
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 21-25, 56-67, 129-130, 162, 164, 167-169, 191
    Rockefeller, John D., Sr. - Memorial at Tarrytown, 56-67, 76
    Rockefeller, Laura Spelman, 122
    Rockefeller Rooms (from 4 West 54th, given to City Museum), 15-16, 24-25, 28-29, 68
    "Rockefeller Women," 27
    740 Park Avenue - Move to, 9, 15-16, 21-22
    Speers, James M., 119
    Tarrytown (See also "Chamber of Commerce" and "JDR, Sr. Memorial"), 2, 9, 69-73, 75, 108, 120, 127-128, 165, 172, 175
    Ten West 54th Street - Move from, 9, 15-16, 21-22
    "Twelve Against the Gods" - "Saturday Evening Post," March 12, 1938, 18-19
    University of Chicago, 8, 121, 127, 176-179, 181, 183-186, 190-192
    USO, 163-165, 173-180
    Versailles, 1
    Vincent, Dr. - Memorial Meeting, 162
    Williamsburg, 27, 33-34, 36, 74, 79, 99, 132, 138-141, 143, 174, 188-189
    World War II (See also USO), 149, 152-154, 156-161, 170, 178
  - Volume 17, October 1941-December 1947 (Reel M 27, Frame M 17)
  - Volume 18, January 1948-October 1954 (Reel M 27, Frame M 18)
  - Volume 19, November 1954-January 1964 (Reel M 27, Frame M 19)
  - Volume 20, May 1960 (Reel M 27, Frame M 20)
  - Volume 21, May 1960 (Reel M 27, Frame M 21)
  - Volume 22, May 1960 (Reel M 27, Frame M 22)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Audiovisual materials, 11
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  When requesting to view films -- please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1902).
  If the item does not have a designated AV number, please refer to the Title and the Film Number (which consists of a combination of Roman numerals and alphanumerics - example: III 14.1-6).
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. (1) (Reel AV 1396)
    All inquiries to view films require advanced notice of at least 24 hours, and may necessitate notice of up to one week. Individual items, including those not available in modern formats, may be restricted from scholarly access at the discretion of RAC.
    File Plan
    III 14.2-22
    Scope and Contents
    Colonial Williamsburg, Virginia: JDR JR with Abby Aldrich Rockefeller; tea party at Bassett Hall; reviewing blueprints with Kenneth Chorley and William Perry; Abby knitting scarf for war effort (May 15, 1942).
    Knitting; Parties; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Colonial Williamsburg (Williamsburg, Va.); Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. (1) (Box 2, Dvd AV 1396)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. (2) (Reel AV 1376)
    Newsreel clips covering the repeal of Prohibition, fingerprinting drive, the completion of Rockefeller Center, and a visit to Versailles in France (1936?). Includes footage from Pathe News, Paramount News, and Fox Movietone.
    III 14.2-11; CAN ALSO LABELED III 14.2 Fd 12
    Building; Fingerprinting; Newsreels; Repeal of legislation; Versailles (France); New York (N.Y.); Prohibition; Rockefeller Center; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Chateau de Versailles (Versailles, France)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. (2) (Box 2, Dvd AV 1376)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. (5) / JOHN D. ROCKEFELLER JR. SPEECH AGAINST 18TH AMENDMENT, 1932 (Reel AV 1710)
    JDR Jr. reads statement regarding the repeal of prohibition and the Republican platform, with Murray Butler (president of Columbia University)
    III 14.2-14; CAN ALSO LABELED III 14.2 FG 14 REEL 15.
    Prohibition; Repeal of legislation; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family (1), 1917 April 3 (Reel AV 1733)
    III 14 F 57
    Scenes of children of John D. Rockefeller Jr. playing at 10 W. 54th Street in New York City inside the house. Laurance and Winthrop Rockefeller riding scooters; Laurance fixing scooter wheel. Shot by Koshiba: children playing with baby David, Babs, reads to baby, boys fix tricycles. Footage of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller with boys and rabbits at Kykuit.
    Children; West Fifty-fourth Street (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
  - JDR Jr. Family Home Movies, 1920s (Reel AV 821)
    III 14 f 3
    Compilation reel: brothers playing & talking with John D. Rockefeller JR. and John D. Rockefeller SR., chauffeur fixing car, boxing matches aboard a ship, restoration projects in France including visit to Versailles, stone masons at work and cathedral restoration, family cookout in Maine, scenes of Abeyton Lodge, all 1920s.
    Amateur films; Children; Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Historic buildings -- Conservation and restoration; Versailles (France); Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller family; Chateau de Versailles (Versailles, France)
  - JDR Jr. Family Home Movies, 1920s (Box 1, Dvd AV 821)
  - JDR Jr. Family Home Movies, 1920s (Box 1, Dvd AV 3.47)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Lincoln Day Speech, 1928 (Reel AV 1947)
    Audio of speech given on the occasion of Abraham Lincoln's birthday. JDR Jr speaks about the 18th Amendment, charity, and general guidelines for good behavior and morality: "Reputation is what people think we are, character is what we really are".
    III 14.2 Fg 13
    Prohibition; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Ethics; Charity; Lincoln Day; Lincoln Day addresses; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Testifies at Oil Inquiry, 1933 (Reel AV 73)
    Summary: newsreels from Congressional Inquiry to Standard Oil: 'Jackson, WY: "Throngs Wait for Glimpse of Famous Witness after Senate Teapot Probe". "JDR JR with Senator Gerald Nye", chairman of the committee investigating oil leases.
    III 14 F24
    Newsreels; Standard Oil Company; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr., 1921-1943 (Reel AV 1365)
    III 14.2-3
    Compilation of JDR JR. footage from China Medical Board Commission visit, European trips,and events in United States. CMBC visitors in Grand Central Station, New York City (August 11, 1921); CMBC visitors in Vancouver, B.C.; CMBC visitors onboard "the Empress of Asia", arriving at Yokohama, Japan; Governor-General of Chosen, Baron Saito, and wife, greet group; JDR JR greeted by Mayor Yoshimatsu of Keijo, korea; sightseeing in Peking with members of the Chinese Bankers' Association; sight in Pai Hai, the Forbidden City; dedication of peking Union Medical College; NYC newsreel: "Rockefeller Center Seen as Center of World Unity"- cornerstone of British Empire building; Versailles, France newsreel: "JDR JR Honored by France" for restoration aid; NYC newsreel: "JDR JR Drives Last Rivet in the World’s Greatest Building Project"; NYC newsreel: "Peace Has a Home" JDR JR founds the International House; Tarrytown NY newsreel: "JDR JR Restores America's Oldest Castle"- Philipsburg Manor; Providence, Rhode Island: JDR JR receives honorary doctorate from Brown University.
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr., 1921-1943 (Box 2, Dvd AV 1365)